# 大家好 我們收到一個神秘的快遞喲
Hi everyone! We received a mysterious parcel today.
# 不知道是甚麼 我們拆開來看一下
I wonder what it is. Let's open it and have a look.
# 哇~
Wa~
# 單兵制(SIC)熱食品 (註︰包著上寫「自熱」，原字幕幾乎都搞錯了)
Self-heat military food for single use
# 這是@中國火箭軍 寄給我們的哦
This is from the Liberation Army Rocket Force. They sent it to us.
# 東風快遞寄過來的
It's sent through Dongfeng Express. (dimunitive name of Dongfeng Missile).
# 制熱食品應該就是
Self-heat food should be kind of,
# 應該就是我們人民的軍隊吃的
should be the food used by our people's army.
# 這個餅乾
The bar...
# 多維能量餅
Multidimensional energy bar
# 壓縮餅乾 吃一點點它就能維持 就不會那麼飢餓
Energy bar. A tiny little bit of it can keep... You won't feel that hungry.
# 只要吃一點點就好啦
A tiny little bit would be enough.
# 多維能量餅 (葡萄乾) (註︰非說話)
Multidimensional energy bar
(Dried Grapefruits)
# 你看 這個就是壓縮餅乾吧
Look! This is the so called energy bar, isn't it?
# 嘗一下 哇 好香
Let me have a try! Wa! Smells good!
# 真的好香啊
Really good!
# 哇 你看
Wa! Look!
# 葡萄味
Grapefruits flavour
# 你看 葡萄乾味 這裡面有葡萄乾的
Look! Dried grapefruits flavour. There are dried grapefruits inside.
# 這個軍糧
This kind of military food,
# 他上山的時候帶一點 特別好
is exceptionally good when they're going onto the mountains.
# 是呀 充飢
Indeed. It can satiate the hunger.
# 呃 吃一點點就能扛的住 扛得住很久
Eh, a tiny little bit of it can allow them to hang in, hang in for a long time.
# 它能充飢哇
Cuz, it can satiate the hunger.
# 吃一塊就飽啦
A single piece is enough make you full.
# 我們的人民解放軍戰士 你看 每次去出差呀 打仗啊
The soldiers of our People's Liberation Amry... Look! Every time when they are out for work, for a war,
# 或者那個訓練之外就吃這個東西
or, you know, training, or whatever, this is what they eat.
# 這個容易充飢哇 方便紐帶 (註︰「紐帶」在這視頻出現了很多次，西瓜和B站的人都沒看明白，所以當「携帶」算了)
This can keep them feel full easily. And it's easy to carry.
# 你看 保家衞國
Look! Protecting our families and our country,
# 都是他們在做 是啊 吃的都是這種
is what they're doing. Yup! And this is what they're eating.
# 還有這種
And also this kind of,
# 這醬料
the sauce...
# 有一個制熱袋 熱的那個飯就直接這樣吃
There is a self-heat pack. You can heat the rice and then eat it right away.
# 特別辛苦
Life is really harsh,
# 在外面
when they're outside.
# 哇 這個是衣服哦
Wa! This is a T-shirt!
# 拆開來
Let me open it,
# 看一下
and have a look.
# 哇瑟 哇 那麼漂亮
Gosh! Wa! It's pretty!
# 正義
Justice
# 天降正義 (註︰這不是說話，但我想解釋一下)
Justice from Heaven
# 你看
Look!
# 正義
Justice
# 東風快遞 使拿必達
Dongfeng Epress, Mission Complete
# 你看 我把這衣服穿上
Look! I'm gonna put on this T-shirt!
# 誒 上面那頭
Eh? The goat up there,
# 兩頭羊都過來啦
both goats are coming.
# 你看 帥不帥
Look! Is it cool?
# 天降正義 (註︰這不是說話，但我想解釋一下)
Justice from Heaven
# 看下下還有甚麼好東西
Let me see what other good stuff are there.
# 誒 這個也是衣服 大的 加大
Eh? These are also T-shirts. This is large size, extra large.
# 哇 還有這個
Wa! Here's also a...
# 你看 這個桌墊 (東風快遞 使命必達 火箭軍) (註︰這不是說話，但我想解釋一下)
Look! This desk pad is,
(Dongfeng Express, Mission Complete. Rocket Army)
# (東風快遞 使命必達 火箭軍)
# 靚吧
beautiful, isn't it?
(Dongfeng Express, Mission Complete. Rocket Army)
# (東風快遞 使命必達 火箭軍)
# 火箭軍
Rocket Army
# 東風快遞 使命必達
Dongfeng Express, Mission Complete
# 這個也可以做 用來做那個 額 鼠標墊的 這個
This can also be, it can be, I mean, eh, a mouse pad, this one.
# 它這很柔軟的 摸起來很舒服
It's really soft. It feels so comfortable.
# 好威武哇
So formidable!
# 我們去加點水來試一下這個
Let me get some water, and try this one.
# 好久沒下雨啦 差不多兩個月都沒下雨
It has been a long time since the last rain, almost two months.
# 現在
And now,
# 好大的雨呀
it's raining heavily.
# 洗一下這裡的灰塵
It can wash away the dust here.
# 吃一下這個飯
Let me try this rice.
# 這個飯輕輕的撕開
The rice, I tear it open here, gently.
# 你看 這是飯哦 這是
Look! This is rice, this is,
# 海鮮 咖喱炒飯
fried rice, with seafood, and curry sauce.
# 這是 兩袋那個
These, two packs are, you know,
# 發熱 發熱片
heating, heating pads.
# 這樣把它裹住
We can wrap it up like this.
# 這樣把它裹住 再放進去
Wrap it up, and then we can put it inside.
# 然後就可以直接放點水 就可以直接發熱啦
Then it can heat, with some water, it can heat up right away.
# 這裡還有一個加熱器用水袋
These is a water bag for the heating pad.
# 裝那麼多水就可以啦 我去裝點那個冷水
I only need to fill the water up here. I'm gonna get some cold water..
# 你看
Look!
# 它畫了綫啦
A line is here.
# 很人性化
It's really user friendly.
# 把這水倒進去
So I pour the water in.
# 然後再把它
And then I'm gonna,
# 蓋起來
cover it up.
# 要快一點啊 快一點 因為現在開始
I gotta be fast, and faster, cuz it's starting to...
# 你看 開始發脹啦
Look! It starts blowing up now.
# 哇
Wa!
# 快不快 好快呀
Isn't it fast? It's really fast!
# 這個溫度好燙的喲
The temperature is really high.
# 都能燙手 這個
It, it burns my hand.
# 先把它蓋起來
Let me cover it up first.
# 這樣放著就可以啦
Place it here and that's it.
# 這個十分鐘以後哇 就可以吃啦
Well, in ten minutes, it will be ready to serve.
# 還有西紅杮蛋湯哦
Here's also tomato soup with egg.
# 藍莓乾
Dried blue berries
# 雞肉香辣醬
Chicken chilli sauce
# 香辣金針菇 等下飯好啦 我就把這個放上去就好啦
Spicy sauce with enokitake. When the rice it ready, I can simply put it onto the rice.
# 這個藍莓乾這應該是
I think the dried blue berries should be,
# 小零食
some kinds of snacks.
# 這個湯
The soup...
# 後面來
Later!
# 在香口香糖 這還有口香糖 (註︰原字幕有錯吧？沒看懂也沒聽懂)
This is chewing gum, there's also chewing gum.
# 口香糖是在路上吃的
They chew the chewing gum, when they're on the way.
# 放這靠一下 靠熱一點
Put it here, closer to the heat.
# 現在好了哦 我把這個飯盒拿出來
It's ready now. I'm gonna take out the rice container.
# 把這個勺子拿出來
I take out the spoon as well.
# 把這飯倒出來 很燙的哦 這個
Let me pour out the rice. It's really hot, the rice.
# 一定要注意 不要燙傷弓手
I need to be very careful. Otherwise it may burn my hands.
# 一個撕口 就這樣撕開
I can simply tear it open, from here.
# 這個溫度可以 超過百度哦 這個
This temperature is not bad. It's over a hundred degrees, you know.
# 超過一百度哦
It's over a hundred degrees.
# 還有 可以把這個配料
Also, I can pour the side ingredients,
# 放進去
onto the rice.
# 金針菇
Enokitake
# 這辣椒醬哦 這個
And this is, this is chilli sauce.
# 你看
Look!
# 這飯就好啦 特別簡單
The rice is now ready. It's really simple.
# 嗯
Um!
# 這個飯好吃
It tastes really good!
# 這還有海鮮哦
There's seafood as well,
# 還有辣椒醬
and chilli sauce too.
# 吃了這個飯很容易補充體力喲
This rice can refuel the body very quickly.
# 而且紐帶起來特別方便
And carrying it is also exceptionally convenient.
# 熱騰騰的
It's boiling hot.
# 還燙手 現在
I can still feel it burning, even now.
# 感謝人民解放軍的辛苦付出
My greatest gratitude to all the hardships and givings of the People's Liberation Army.
# 守護我們的祖國每一寸土地
It's all because of their protection of every single inch of soil of our Motherland,
# 才有我們今天的美好生活
that we can enjoy our beautiful and fruitful lives nowadays.
# 祝我們的國家繁榮昌盛 越來越強大
I wish our Motherland forever prosperity, and endless blossoming.